https://www.cortera.com/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy
Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way the information obtained through this website is collected and used.
This notice applies primarily to personal information collected by Cortera from users of our website, www.cortera.com. Except as expressly set forth below, this notice does not apply to information contained in the business profiles displayed through this website.
Our website contains links to other websites operated by third parties. Cortera is not responsible for the online information practices or policies of such third party websites, and this notice does not apply to those websites.
Cortera is subject to the investigatory and enforcement authority of the US Federal Trade Commission (FTC).
Information We Collect and How We Use It
Information Displayed in Cortera Business Profiles.
Cortera collects information about businesses to produce the business profiles displayed through this website.  Cortera primarily collects this business information offline.  This business information may include the names and contact information for business owners or executives, such as postal addresses, email addresses, or phone numbers (“Public Information”).  Some of this Public Information comes from federal, state, or local government public records.
Information Collected from Your Use of this Website.
We use commercially reasonable efforts to ensure that the collection of personal information from your use of this website is limited to that which is necessary to fulfill the purposes identified below. If we use your information in a manner different than the purpose for which it is collected, then we will ask you for your consent prior to such use.
Account Setup. If you create an account to take advantage of the full range of services offered on this website, we ask for and record personal information such as your name, address, phone number, and email address. We use your email address to send you updates and news, and contact you at the request of other users (such as other registered users who wish to contact you about a rating you have submitted). Your contact information will not be shared with other users.
Logging in to Use Features. In a few areas on our website, we also ask you to provide information that will enable us to verify whether you are entitled to access and use certain information, materials and services available from our website. It is completely optional for you to participate. However, failure to participate may mean that you cannot access and use certain information, materials and services. These include areas where users log on to certain areas of our website, at which point you may be prompted to provide us with your User ID code and password as a condition to gaining access to certain information, materials or services.
Submissions. We store and may publicly display your submissions in order to provide the services that we offer. When we display your submissions, we do so together with the user identification code (the “User ID”) you have established. If we display your submission, we may also contact you at the request of other users who wish to discuss your submission with you. We will not reveal your contact information to other users. The term “submissions” refers to the information that you submit or post to the website for public display, such as business ratings and reviews.
Requests to Contact Other Users. If you request that Cortera contact another registered user on your behalf to discuss a submission, we will share your email address with such other registered user. The decision of whether another registered user wishes to respond to you rests solely with that user.
Feedback. If you contact us to provide feedback, update a business listing, dispute a payment rating, or ask a question, we will record any personal information and other content that you provide in your communication so that we can effectively respond to your communication.
Cortera Marketing Use. We may contact you and send you promotional materials about Cortera and its products and services via mail and email.
Activity. We record information relating to your use of the website, such as the searches you undertake, the pages you view, your browser type, IP address, requested URL, referring URL, and timestamp information. We use this type of information to administer the website and provide the highest possible level of service to you. We also use this information in the aggregate to perform statistical analyses of user behavior and characteristics in order to measure interest in and use of the various areas of the website.
Cookies. We design the layout and features of our website so that new visitors may anonymously learn about our products and services without revealing their identities. For new visitors, we use cookies to collect limited data, such as the date, time and areas of our website that are visited, as well as the website from which the new visitor came. When you select one of our products or services, register with n or complete a survey, we may try to identify your browser and we may combine information from cookies with other information collected online. By improving the features, marketing, and content of our website and by making your online experience more convenient and meaningful, we are able to better serve our customers’ needs.
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your computer’s hard drive and that often includes an anonymous unique identifier. When you visit a website, that website’s computer asks your computer for permission to store this text file in a section of your hard drive that is specifically designated for cookies. Each website can send its own cookie to your browser if your browser’s preferences allow it. Your browser will only permit a website to access the cookies that it has previously sent to you and not the cookies sent to you by other websites. Some of our business partners, such as third party advertisers, use cookies that originate from their websites. We have no access to, or control over, these cookies. We use cookies to store login or other information on your computer, which serves to improve our website functionality and tailor our services to your preferences and interests. For certain services, we offer users the ability to store a user ID or password within a cookie so that they do not need to re-enter it when they subsequently return to our website. Cookies, in conjunction with our Web server’s log files, allow us to calculate the aggregate number of people visiting our website and to assess which parts of the site are most popular. This information helps us to constantly improve our website and better serve our customers. Most Internet browsers allow users to decide whether to accept cookies and how long to keep them on their hard drive. You may reset your browser to refuse cookies and still use our website, although website access and functionality may be slower and less convenient.
Third Party Advertising. We use a third party advertising service called Google Adsense to serve ads when you visit our website. In the course of serving advertisements, Google Adsense may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser. Google Adsense may use information about your visits to Cortera and other websites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. Google Adsense may use information about your visits to our website and other websites to measure the effectiveness of ads. We do not disclose any personally identifiable information to Google Adsense.
Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) is a self-regulatory cooperative of online marketing and analytics companies. The NAI provides educational content and opt-out tools to help Internet users learn about and address online behavioral marketing practices. Through the NAI’s online options, you may opt out of particular NAI network members’ behavioral advertising programs or you may opt out of all NAI network members’ programs. Opting out will prevent the given network from which you opted out from using your Web preferences and usage patterns to deliver targeted online ads. The NAI opt-out only works with participating third party advertising networks that use cookies to execute their advertising initiatives. If you would like additional information about online behavioral marketing and your options regarding these standard Internet practices, please visit the NAI website.
Other Cookies. We may also use cookies and other technologies from Google Analytics, Hotjar, Triblio, and other third parties that allow us to better understand how visitors use our website.
Enforcement. We may use the information we collect in connection with your use of the website (including your personal information) in order to investigate, enforce, and apply our Terms and Privacy Notice.
Transfer of Information
We may distribute your submissions to third parties, as permitted pursuant to our Terms. When we distribute your submissions to third parties, we typically include your User ID, but we generally do not include your personal information unless you include your personal information in your submissions. However, there may be exceptions where your name and email address domain is shared with other members of the website when you elect to participate in discussions with other members (an email address domain refers to the email service that you use; e.g., Gmail, Yahoo, etc.) For example, within the Cortera Circles offering, if you create or reply to a discussion thread, your first and last name will be displayed along with your submission to the members of your Cortera Circle. Another example is, if you apply to join a Cortera Circle, your name and email address domain will be displayed to the manager of that Cortera Circle so that the manager can evaluate your application to join the Cortera Circle.
We may share your personal information with third parties to provide you with services that we offer through the website, conduct quality assurance testing, facilitate creation of accounts, provide technical and customer support, email or contact you, or provide other specific services in accordance with your instructions. These third parties are required not to use your personal information other than to provide the services requested by you.
If you request that Cortera contact another registered user on your behalf to discuss a submission, we will share your email address with such other registered user so that such other use can reply directly to you.
We may share your personal information with our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, “Affiliates“) that we may have now or in the future, in which case we will require them to honor this Privacy Notice. If another company acquires our company or our assets, that company will possess your personal information, and will assume the rights and obligations with respect to that information as described in this Privacy Notice.
We may disclose your personal information to third parties in a good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to (a) take action regarding suspected illegal activities; (b) enforce or apply our Terms and Privacy Notice; (c) comply with legal process, such as a search warrant, subpoena, statute, or court order; or (d) protect our rights, reputation, and property, or that of our users, affiliates, or the public. Please note that we are not required to question or contest the validity of any search warrant, subpoena or other similar governmental request that we receive. Cortera may be required to disclose EU and/or Swiss personal data in response to a lawful request by public authorities including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.
We may disclose information in the aggregate to third parties relating to user behavior in connection with actual or prospective business relationship with those third parties, such as advertisers and content distributors. For example, we may disclose the number of users that have been exposed to, or clicked on, advertising banners.
Cortera may be liable for the appropriate onward transfer of personally identifiable data of EU and Swiss individuals.
Responding to Inquiries from Other Users
If we display your submission, we may contact you at the request of other registered users who wish to discuss your submission with you. The decision of whether you wish to respond to another user will lie solely with you. Should you elect to respond to another user, your response will be transmitted outside of this website; accordingly, this Privacy Notice will not apply to your response. If you respond to another user, that user may be able to identify you and you hereby agree to assume all risks associated therewith.
Information of Others
You may choose to provide us with another person’s e-mail address so that person may be invited to create an account on this website. By providing us with another person’s e-mail address, you represent to us that you have obtained the consent of the person concerned as regards such disclosure to us of their personal information. All invitees are provided with the option not to receive further invitations. We may disclose such information if required to do so in order to comply with legal process, as described above.
You Can Opt Out of Receiving Further Marketing from Cortera at Any Time
We will send you information about our various products and services, or other products and services we feel may be of interest to you. Only Cortera (or agents or contractors working on behalf of Cortera and under confidentiality agreements) will send you these direct mailings. At any time, you can easily opt out of receiving further marketing from Cortera by emailing us at privacy@cortera.com or by clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of our emails.
Our Commitment to Data Security
Your account is password protected. We use industry standard measures to protect the personal information that is stored in our database. We limit the access to your personal information to those employees and contractors who need access to perform their job function, such as our customer service personnel. Although we take appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial measures to safeguard against unauthorized disclosures of information, we cannot assure you that your personal information will never be disclosed in a manner that is inconsistent with this Privacy Notice.
You hereby acknowledge that Cortera is not responsible for any intercepted information sent via the internet, and you hereby release us from any and all claims arising out of or related to the use of intercepted information in any unauthorized manner.
Changes to Privacy Notice
We may modify this Privacy Notice at any time, and we will post any new versions on this page. If we make any material changes in the way we use your personal information, we will notify you by sending an e-mail to the last e-mail address you provided to us and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our website. Any such changes will be effective upon the earlier of thirty (30) calendar days following our dispatch of an e-mail notice to you or thirty (30) calendar days following our posting of notice of the changes on our website. These changes will be effective immediately for new users of this website. Please note that at all times you are responsible for updating your personal information to provide us with your most current e-mail address. In the event that the last e-mail you have provided us is not valid, or for any reason is not capable of delivering to you the notice described above, our dispatch of the e-mail containing such notice will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the changes described in the notice. In any event, changes to this Privacy Notice may affect our use of personal information that you provided us prior to our notification to you of the changes. If you do not wish to permit changes in our use of your personal information, you must notify us prior to the effective date of the changes that you wish to deactivate your account with us. Continued use of this website following notice of such changes shall indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.
How You Can Access or Correct Your Information; Choice About Use and Disclosure
Cortera acknowledges the individual’s right to access their personal data.  You can request a copy of the personally-identifiable information that Cortera has collected about you via the website by emailing us at privacy@cortera.com. You can also request to have factual inaccuracies in this information corrected by emailing us at privacy@cortera.com.  You also have the right to limit use and disclosure of your personal data, subject to certain exceptions. To exercise this right, please email us at privacy@cortera.com.  If you wish for Cortera to stop emailing you, please use the opt-out function at the bottom of the email.  Please note that where Cortera is acting as a processor of personal data for a customer, Cortera may first refer your request to the customer that submitted your personal data, and Cortera will assist the customer as needed in responding to your request.
Privacy Shield (EU-US and Swiss-US)
Cortera complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland, respectively. Cortera has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement, and Liability. If there is any conflict between the policies in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov/.
The types of information that Cortera collects and the purposes for which such information is used is described above in the section entitled “Information We Collect and How We Use It.”
In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, Cortera commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact Cortera at:
Attention: Privacy Officer
Cortera, Inc.
901 Yamato Road, Suite 210E
Boca Raton, FL 33431
USA
privacy@cortera.com
Cortera has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US Privacy Shield Principles and the Swiss-US Privacy Shield to BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, a non-profit alternative dispute resolution provider located in the United States and operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers/ for more information and to file a complaint.
Note that as a last resort and under limited circumstances EU and Swiss individuals with unresolved complaints can invoke binding arbitration before the Privacy Shield Panel.
California Privacy Rights Disclosure
This Privacy Policy describes Cortera’s handling of personally identifiable information as required by the California Online Privacy Protection Act and personal information under the California Consumer Privacy Act.  California residents have the additional rights described in this section.
Under California Civil Code Section 1798.83, also known as Senate Bill 27, or Shine the Light you are entitled to request and receive, free of charge, a copy of Cortera’s California Information Sharing Disclosure Notice for the previous calendar year. You may print this page, or call (561) 226-9000, to request a copy or email us at privacy@cortera.com. We will provide the requested information to you at your email address in response. Please be aware that not all information sharing is covered by the “Shine the Light” requirements and only information on covered sharing will be included in our response.
You have the right to opt-out from the sale of your personal information.  Cortera does not sell personal information collected from your use of this website.  However, you have the right to opt-out of the sale of Public Information.  To make an opt-out request related to Public Information, call 1 (888) 552-4457 during Cortera’s business hours or click here: https://www.cortera.com/do-not-sell-my-info.  California law excludes information from federal, state, and local government agencies from the scope of opt-out requests.  While Cortera will not sell Public Information that has been opted-out, Cortera reserves the right to disclose Public Information to third parties, without notice to you, if required to do so by law, or if Cortera has a good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to (1) comply with legal process served on Cortera; (2) protect and defend Cortera’s rights or property; or (3) act in an emergency to protect someone’s safety.  Cortera also reserves the right to transfer Public Information to any successor in interest to the Cortera business.  An authorized agent may make a request on your behalf.  The authorized agent may be required to provide Cortera with a copy of a signed power of attorney or other signed, written document authorizing the agent to make the request on your behalf.
You also have the right to request that Cortera disclose to you what personal information Cortera collects, uses, and/or discloses. To make a right-to-know request related to Public Information, call 1 (888) 552-4457  during Cortera’s business hours or click here: https://see.cortera.com/privacy-contact-center.  To make a right-to-know request related to personal information collected from your use of this website, call 1 (888) 552-4457 during Cortera’s business hours.  California law excludes information from federal, state, and local government agencies from the scope of right-to-know requests.  An authorized agent may make a request on your behalf.  The authorized agent may be required to provide Cortera with a copy of a signed power of attorney or other signed, written document authorizing the agent to make the request on your behalf.
Cortera will not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under this section of this Privacy Policy.
How to Contact Us
If you would like to contact us for any reason regarding our online information practices, please email us at privacy@cortera.com.
Last updated: March 20, 2020
